GREGORY HODGE

Web/Software Developer & Designer

St Thomas, VI 00802 ghodge.vi@gmail.com 3409986956

Hi! My name is Gregory. I am a Web Developer from the Caribbean (US Virgin Islands) that has a passion for coding and design. I've attended the University of the Virgin Islands & NuCamp Coding Academy. Professionally I have over 10 years working experience in the Communications, Designs, Media and Marketing fields. I'm a great team worker that can be an incredible asset to your company.

Willing to relocate: Anywhere

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

Work Experience

Web/Software Developer/ Video & Graphic Designer/ Media Marketing Specialist

Avalanche Media - Saint Thomas, VI September 2017 to Present

- Developed client side web applications with the use of HTML, CSS/SASS/SCSS, Bootstrap, Bulma, JavaScript, NodeJS, ReactJS, React Native, VueJS, APIs, Git & Electron.
- Produced Marketing, Media and Digital Content Creation tools like Adobe Premier, Sony Vegas, Adobe Audition etc..
- Created graphical designs for clients using Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator etc

Production Manager

Ackley Media Group - Saint Thomas, VI October 2006 to September 2017

- Pre-Record and Broadcast live on On-Air Programs
- Managing radio production and imaging studio, voicing and produce commercial content for clients, Utilizing single and multi-track production software like Adobe Audition, Ableton Live and similar like DAW's
- Monitor commercials and transmitter logs, ensuring that promotions and contests are executed properly
- Creating On-Air Music Playlists and On-Air Mixshow Playlists and Mixes
- Personal appearances at station, community events and remote broadcasts
- Operating the control board, and on-air programming stations and software such as Enco and Radio DJ

Security Screener

Department of Homeland Security - Saint Thomas, VI November 2001 to October 2006

- Conduct screening of passengers, baggage, or cargo to ensure compliance with Transportation Security Administration (TSA) regulations
- Operate basic security equipment such as x-ray machines and hand wands at screening checkpoints

Desktop Publisher/Graphic Designer

Office Max/ Depot - Saint Thomas, VI January 1999 to November 2001

- Edit graphics, designs and work with clients and writers to create new artwork or text documents
- Check proofs, or preliminary layouts, for errors and make corrections
- Finalize formatted documents for printing or electronic publication

Sales Associate

Kinney Shoes - Saint Thomas, VI August 1997 to January 1999

- Delivering outstanding customer service and offering a distinct shopping experience
- Working as part of a team to meet department's and store's objectives
- Organizing the selling floor and stock areas
- Keeping the selling floor stocked with merchandise for sales events

Education

Coding Bootcamp/Academy Graduate in Front End Web + Mobile Development

Nucamp Coding Bootcamp - Tacoma, WA

October 2020 to Present

Skills

- Software Development
- HTML5
- · Graphic Design
- JavaScript
- CSS
- Git
- Bootstrap
- React
- Node.js
- Application Development
- GitHub
- Adobe Photoshop
- REST
- APIs
- JSON
- User Interface (UI)

Certifications and Licenses

HTML/CSS/JavaScript

Present

Certifies proficiency in web designing using HTML/CSS & JavaScript languages .

Responsive Web Design

Present

Certifies proficiency in the development of Responsive Web applications.

Front End Web Development - Boostrap

Present

Certifies proficiency in client side css framwork technology.

Front End Web Development - React JS

Present

Certifies proficiency in client side JavaScript framwork technology.

Assessments

Software developer fit — Highly Proficient

January 2021

Measures the traits that are important for successful software developers

Full results: Highly Proficient

Attention to detail — Highly Proficient

November 2020

Identifying differences in materials, following instructions, and detecting details among distracting information

Full results: <u>Highly Proficient</u>

Indeed Assessments provides skills tests that are not indicative of a license or certification, or continued development in any professional field.